Something evil has returned to Hogwarts!
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets is a adventure,
fantasy film directed by Chris Columbus.
Cars fly, trees fight back, and a mysterious house-elf comes to warn
Harry Potter at the start of his second year at Hogwarts.
Adventure and danger await when bloody writing on a wall
announces: The Chamber Of Secrets Has Been Opened.
To save Hogwarts will require all of Harry, Ron and
Hermione's magical abilities and courage.
Harry Potter, played by Daniel Radcliffe.
Ron Weasley, played by Rupert Grint.
Hermione Granger, played by Emma Watson.
Gilderoy Lockhart, played by Kenneth Branagh.
Dobby (voice), played by Toby Jones.
Rubeus Hagrid, played by Robbie Coltrane.
Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets is a 2002 fantasy film directed
by Chris Columbus from a screenplay by Steve Kloves.
It is based on the 1998 novel Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets by J.
Produced by David Heyman, it is the sequel to Harry Potter and the Philosopher's
Stone (2001) and the second instalment in the Harry Potter film series.
The film stars Daniel Radcliffe as Harry Potter, with Rupert Grint and Emma Watson
as his best friends Ron Weasley and Hermione Granger respectively.
The story follows Harry's second year at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry, where the Heir of Salazar
Slytherin opens the Chamber of Secrets, unleashing a monster that petrifies the school's students.
The film was released in the United Kingdom and the United
States on 15 November 2002, by Warner Bros.
It became a critical and commercial success, grossing $878 million worldwide (domestic 29.7%
and foreign 70.2%) and becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2002.
The film was nominated for many awards, including the BAFTA Award for Best
Production Design, Best Sound, and Best Special Visual Effects.
It was followed by Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban (2004).
The film explores themes of witch, flying car, elves, magic, sword.